狙击手：白乌鸦
字幕翻译 - 静默的风
如转载使用  请保留译者信息
翻译字幕纯属学习交流
不作商业用途
我要迟到了...
I'll be late...
所以  得走了
So. Let's go!
早上好
Good morning.
早上好  塔拉斯
Good morning, Taras.
-早上好   - 下午好
- Good morning!   - Good afternoon!
早上好
Good morning!
好的
Good...
下午好
Good afternoon.
早上好
Good morning!
-那是我的日志吗   - 是的  拿着
- Is that my journal?   - Yes, take it.
米科拉  你脸上有东西
Mykola, you have something on your cheek.
亚努科维奇拒绝与欧盟签署协议
Yanukovych refused to sign   an agreement with the EU
并制定与俄罗斯改善关系的计划
and set a course   for improving relations with Russia.
最大规模的抗议活动发生在基辅的独立广场
The largest protest took place   on Maidan in Kyiv,
特种部队杀害了100多名抗议者
the special forces killed   more than 100 protesters.
看  狙击手...
Look, a sniper...
乌克兰总统维克托·亚努科维奇逃往俄罗斯
President of Ukraine,   Viktor Yanukovych fled to Russia,
辞去总司令职务
leaving his post as Commander-in-Chief.
克里米亚完全被占领
Crimea was completely captured
并由俄罗斯联邦控制
and taken under the control   of the Russian Federation.
* 克里米亚 *
CRIMEA
速度是一个物理量
Velocity is a physical quantity
这就是运动的特点
that characterizes the motion
以及物体在单位时间内移动的距离
and distance that   an object travels per unit of time.
计算速度
The velocity is calculated
通过公式V=S/t
by the formula V=S/t.
其中V是速度...
Where V is the speed...
- 你是个白痴吗   - 闭上你的嘴  同性恋
- Are you a moron?   - Shut your mouth, faggot!
伊凡...
Ivan...
S是距离
S is distance.
t是时间
And t is time.
你能在同一个地方再次击中吗
Can you hit in the same place again?
重置计时器吗
RESET TIMER?
0.9秒
0.9 seconds.
我测量了  七米的距离
I measured a distance of seven meters.
伊凡  速度是多少
Ivan, what is the speed?
塔拉斯...
Taras...
每秒7.8米
7.8 meters per second.
对
Yes.
它是以这样的速度
It was at this speed
伊凡吐出一团纸
that Ivan spat out a piece of paper.
嗯  伊凡...
Well, Ivan...
如果时间不是0.9秒  而是0.7秒
if the time is not 0.9, but 0.7
在相同的距离...
at the same distance...
速度是多少
What would the speed be?
把答案写在黑板上
Write the answer on the board.
有答案吗
Is there an answer?
现在很清楚是什么让你分心了...
Now it's clear   what you are distracted by...
再见
Goodbye.
再见  塔拉斯
Goodbye, Taras.
听着  挖掘机…
Listen, digger...
你说什么
I'm sorry?
你是这里的外地人  滚蛋吧
You're a stranger here, get out.
利奥沙  你准备好了吗
Lyosha, are you ready?
是的
Yes.
沃罗年科一家是顿巴斯的第一批生态移民
The Voronenko family   are the first eco-settlers in Donbas.
一年前  他们注册了一块两公顷的土地
A year ago,   they registered a two-hectare plot of land
并搬到田野里居住
near Horlivka   and moved to live in a field.
米科拉有三个高等教育学位  数学  物理学和生态学
Mykola has three higher education degrees,   mathematician, physicist, and ecologist.
解释一下是什么原因导致你采取如此激进的手段
Explain what caused   you to take such a radical step?
作为一名生态学家  我明白艰难的时刻在等着我们
As an ecologist, I understand   that difficult times await us.
只有将有害的生活方式转变为生态的生活方式
Only by changing the harmful way   of life to an ecological one,
我们能有机会拯救地球和我们自己吗
can we have a chance   to save the planet and ourselves.
你们打算在这里住多久
How long do you plan to live here?
我们想在这里生养孩子
We want to have and raise a child here.
你妻子怀孕了吗
Is your wife pregnant?
是的
Yes.
这意味着一切都会好起来的
This means   everything will work out just fine.
告诉我  这是什么标志
Tell me, what is this sign?
这是我们祖先的标志
This is our ancestral sign.
这表达了什么意思
And what does it mean?
一只白鸦的爪子
Paw of a white raven.
你能告诉我吗
Will you tell me?
- 这是...一个古老的...     - 把麦克风靠近点。
- This is... an ancient...   - Get the microphone closer.
让我拿着
Let me hold it.
传说...
Legend...
乌鸦在黑暗中创造了世界  挥舞着他的翅膀
Raven created the world   out of darkness, waving his wings.
世界是有海岸的黑色海洋
And the world is   a black ocean with a shore,
人们很快就会来这里居住
where people will soon come to live.
乌鸦同情人们
The raven, feeling pity for the people,
把海水变成淡水和食物
turns the ocean's salty water   into fresh water and food,
但作为回报...
but in return...
牺牲了雪白的羽毛
sacrifices its snow-white feathers.
谢谢
Thank you.
利奥沙  停下
Lesha, stop.
进来吧  现在我带你们进去...
Come on in, now I'll show you inside...
这是一架风车
And this is a windmill.
我可以晚点告诉你  顺便说一下  这是我自己做的
I can tell you later about it,   by the way, I made it myself.
我们从这台发电机开始好吗
Shall we start with a dynamo machine?
我来告诉你它是如何工作的...
I'll show you how it works...
看到了吗
See?
利奥沙  再拍一些细节和这些草图
Lyosha, film just a few more details   and these sketches.
在这里生孩子  你不怕吗
And you're not afraid to give birth here?
不  我不怕
No, I'm not afraid.
嗯…
Hmm...
莉娜
Lena,
- 我想我们结束吧   - 是的  我们结束了
- I hope we are done?   - Yes, we're done.
- 我还没有全部展示给你们看...   - 尼古拉  谢谢你  我们得到的已经足够
- I haven't shown you everything yet...   - Nikolai, thank you, we've had enough.
两个疯狂的人
Two crazy people.
东西掉了
Something fell out.
我们在这里不扔垃圾
We do not throw trash here.
再见
Goodbye.
我们走吧
Let's go.
别担心
Don't worry,
总有一天一切都会恢复正常
someday everything   will come back to normal.
♪ 跟我来，我亲爱的 ♪
Come with me, my dear love
♪ 去一个星光灿烂的地方 ♪
To a place with shining stars
♪ 有江河  有山川  生活充满了爱 ♪
There are rivers, mountains live on love
♪ 鸟儿为我们歌唱 ♪
The birds sing for us
♪ 你的眼睛像蓝宝石那样闪闪发光 ♪
Your eyes are shining like emeralds
♪ 在夏天的不幸中消失 ♪
And disappeared   In the misfortune of summer
♪ 我会给你整个世界 ♪
I will give you the whole world
♪ 还有一个叫娜斯提亚的女儿 ♪
And a daughter with the name Nastya
♪ 我会给你整个世界 ♪
I will give you the whole world
♪ 还有个女儿叫...♪
And a daughter with the name...
♪ 娜斯提亚...♪
Nastya...
这是我们送给您的
This is for you from us.
你的小天使
Your Little Angel.
会保护你
Will protect you.
总部  我们通过边境线
Buriy, we pass the line.
已确认  摘掉臂章
Confirmed. Chevrons.
* 注意！乌克兰国家边界禁止通行 *
CAUTION!   STATE BORDER OF UKRAINE. NO PASSAGE.
起来  快点
Get up, be fast!
好了  我来了  我来了...
Yes, I'm coming, I'm coming...
再见
Bye.
噢  一个不错的引擎
Oh, a normal engine!
飞起来
Flying!
我飞了...
I'm flying...
是的  一切都取消了
Yes, everything was canceled.
不  我不知道...
No, I don't know...
也许不会...
Maybe it won't be...
好的  我把它关闭了
Yes, I'll close it.
今天早上，一辆不知名的公共汽车停了下来
This morning, an unknown bus stopped
在顿涅茨克地区的霍尔夫卡警察局附近
near the Horlivka Police Department   in the Donetsk region.
还注意到头戴巴拉克拉法帽的武装分子
It is also noted that   armed militants in balaclavas
与亲俄分子
and pro-Russian activists
继续维护着在斯拉夫扬斯克、克拉马托斯克和顿涅茨克地区的
continue to maintain the buildings   of regional state administrations
国家行政机构的大楼
in Slovyansk, Kramatorsk, and Donetsk.
还有…
And...
很明显  乌克兰国防部情报总局的特种部队
It just became clear   that special forces of GUR
俄罗斯联邦的代理人参与
of the Russian Federation took part
抓捕了克里米亚的最高拉达
in the capture   of the Rada Verkhovna of Crimea.
别碰她
Take your hands off of her!
你是谁
Who are you?
婊子
Bitch!
你在这里干什么  野人
What are you doing here, khokhlyara?
我是一名教师  我住在这里
I'm a teacher, I live here.
你是和平主义者吗
Are you a pacifist or something?
- 他是谁   - 我丈夫
- Who is he?   - My husband.
用俄语  操  说话
In Russian, fuck, just talk!
丈夫...
Husband...
别碰她  她怀孕了
Don't touch her, she is pregnant!
这是什么
And what is this?
那些是我的画
Those are my drawings.
看她的相貌  她绝对是个间谍
Look at her face, she's definitely a spy!
站起来
Stand!
不许叫
Don't squeal!
各位  我们走吧
Everyone, let's go.
他怎么了
What about him?
我说  我们走吧
We are leaving, I said.
婊子
Bitch!
他妈的
Fuck!
快上车
Get in the car quickly.
求你了  别死...
Please don't die...
别死  我在这里...
Don't die, I'm here...
我和你在一起  不  不...
I'm here with you. No, no...
不
No!
当地的
Local?
证件呢
Documents?
在包里
In the bag.
她是谁
Who is she?
妻子
Wife.
米科拉·沃罗年科...
Mykola Voronenko...
看来他是我们的人
Looks like he is ours.
来吧
Come on.
我不管那里发生了什么
I don't care what happened there!
他他妈为什么来这里?
Why the fuck is he here?
那我应该把他留在野地里吗?
So, I should have left him   in the middle of the field?
我搞不懂了  如果是他们的间谍呢
I do not understand.   And if it's their spy?
你想过吗
Have you thought about that?
当然  你还没想到
Well, of course,   you haven't thought about it.
你脑子进水了
Your head just doesn't work that way.
但你显然不知道
But you are clearly not aware of that.
所以  给我听好了  带他离开这里  越远越好
So, listen to me carefully.   Take him away from here as far as...
慢着...
Stop...
你开车送他来的时候  把他的眼睛蒙上了吗
Did you blindfold him   when you drove him to us?
什么  你一点脑子都没有吗
What? Do you have no brain at all?
你把我们的基地泄露给了他  你个白痴
You leaked our base to him, you idiot!
现在我应该毙了他吗
Should I shoot him now?
啊  走开...你个混蛋
Ah, go away... you motherfucker!
瘦子
Skinny,
我怎么跟你说的
what did I tell you?
拿着武器上厕所
Go to the toilet   with a weapon in your hand!
这是正确的
That's right!
你为什么要拿枪
Why are you reaching for your gun?
你想自杀吗
Do you want to shoot yourself?
我们得把他们赶出去
We need to drive them out.
他说什么?
What did he say?
我想把他们赶出我们的土地
I want to drive them out of our land.
- 猎鹰在空中飞翔   - 猎鹰在空中飞翔
- Falcons flutter in the sky.   - Falcons flutter in the sky.
- 我们的小队飞向战场   - 我们的小队飞向战场
- Our squad flies into battle.   - Our squad flies into battle.
- 我们将打败敌人   - 我们将打败敌人
- We will defeat the enemies.   - We will defeat the enemies.
- 尽管他们从四面八方爬来   - 尽管他们从四面八方爬来
- Although they crawl from all sides.   - Although they crawl from all sides.
快点  伙计们  快点
Come on, guys, come on.
加快速度   速度  速度  我说  快点
Faster. Tempo, tempo I said! Come on!
巴德
Bad!
就像你那样
As you were!
给他看
Show him.
就像你那样
As you were!
就这样  同志
That's it, comrade!
快点  快点  伙计们  快点
Come on, come on, men, faster!
Thirty-three,
34...
thirty-four...
- 35   - 保持身体挺直
- Thirty-five!   - Keep the body straight.
Thirty-six!
Thirty-seven!
现在休息一下
And now have a rest!
你喜欢以和平主义者的身份待在这里吗
Well, do you enjoy being here   as a pacifist?
是的  长官  指挥官先生
Yes, sir, Mr. Commander!
听你这么说我很高兴
I'm glad to hear that.
请允许我发言  长官  指挥官先生
Permission to speak, sir, Mr. Commander!
允许
Permitted.
我不是和平主义者  指挥官先生
I'm not a pacifist, Mr. Commander.
我的代号是乌鸦
My code name is Raven!
死乌鸦
Dead Raven!
我说了一半
I said one and a half!
这个代号还需要努力争取  同志
This code name still needs   to be earned, comrade.
你明白吗
Do you understand?
是  长官  指挥官先生
Yes, sir, Mr. Commander!
上士
Chief.
疯了吗
Crazy?
嘿  伙计  要喝茶吗
Hey, bud, you want tea?
你呢
And you?
别睡着了
Don't sleep!
快  再快点...
Quickly, quickly...
姑娘们  别被胸罩卡住了
Girls, don't get caught in your bras!
当你们还像和平主义者挤在一起时  战争也就结束了
The war will come to an end while you are   still swarming like a pacifist!
重新开始  拆卸
Start again! Disassemble!
迅速  不要停留
Quickly! Let's not linger!
Twenty-eight,
29...
twenty-nine...
- 压低   - 40...
- Lower!   - Forty...
注意
Attention!
前线没有足够的狙击手
There are not enough snipers at the front.
志愿者组织免费课程  你们感兴趣吗
Volunteers organize free courses.   Are you interested?
巴德  克里姆  杜内  好
Bad, Klym, Dunay, good.
什么  和平主义者  你也是   坐下吧
What? A pacifist? You too? Sit down.
我  列兵乌鸦  请求加入
I, private Raven, ask to join!
听着  你都不知道怎么从AK上卸弹匣
Listen, you don't know   how to remove a magazine from the AK!
你是一个狙击手吗
Which of you is a sniper?
让我展示给你看
Let me show you!
有趣  你能给我们看什么
Interesting. And what can you show us?
20秒内拆卸AK
Disassembly-assembly of AK in 20 seconds.
20秒以内吗
In 20 seconds?
这应该会很有趣
This should be fun.
好吧
Well,
你自己恳求的
you asked yourself.
来吧
Come on.
好吧  战士...准备好了吗
Well, warrior... ready?
好
Well.
开始
Come on!
好
Well.
恭喜列兵乌鸦...
Congratulations to Private Raven...
18秒
Eighteen seconds!
干得好  好极了
Well done! Bravo!
干得好!
Well done!
这是我所理解的。
That's what I understand.
给他找一支SKS（苏制半自动步枪）
Find him one SKS.
右转  起步走
Right turn! March!
没人喜欢狙击手
Nobody likes snipers
因为他们阴险而优雅
because they are insidious and elegant.
没有阻止他们发动战争的方法
There are no forbidden methods   of waging war for them.
专业狙击手的伪装作战  不需要现代的特殊装备
Professional snipers work in disguise   without modern special equipment.
它们的位置几乎不可能被探测到
Their position   is almost impossible to detect.
尤其是在...
Especially...
没有听到枪声  或者枪声被其他噪音掩盖的情况下
if no shots are heard   or they are hidden under another noise.
打扰一下
Excuse me,
这是什么意思
what does that mean?
为了不被抓到  狙击手会在机枪开火
In order not to get caught,   the sniper fires his shot
或爆炸声中开枪
during a machine gun fire   or the sound of explosions.
下一个
Next!
布加维奇
Budkevych.
- 下一个   - 杜纳耶夫斯基
- Next!   - Dunaevsky.
下一个
Next!
沃罗年科
Voronenko.
下一个
Next!
- 这是什么   - 一匹穿着外套的马
- What is this?   - A horse in a coat!
这是SKS  "西蒙诺夫的半自动步枪"
This is SKS.   "Simonov's self-loading carbine"!
下一个
Next!
这是个错误
This is a mistake.
我得像其他人一样有个SVD（德拉贡诺夫设计的狙击步枪）
I have to have an SVD like everybody else.
亲爱的  这里不需要唱歌  这对你来说是马戏团吗
Dear, no need for songs here!   Is it a circus for you here?
我看起来像小丑吗
Do I look like a clown?
他妈的  这是军队
This is, the fucking, army!
你的任务是拿起该死的枪   然后他妈的离开这里
Your task is to pick up the fucking gun   and get the fuck out of here!
我可以去吗
Can I go?
这是什么...爆能枪（电影《星球大战》的一种科幻武器）  操
What is this... Blaster, fuck!
我们都是太空海盗  我操
And we are all space pirates here,   for fuck's sake!
别笑
Don't giggle!
士兵  我不会重复一遍
Soldiers, I do not repeat anything twice.
没人会在这里跟你扯淡
Nobody is going to jerk off with you here!
下一个
Next!
听着  乌鸦
Look, Raven.
能用你的爆能枪给我一枪吗
Will you give me your Blaster for a shot?
狙击手的基本原则是在任何情况下都要保持隐身
The basic rule of a sniper is to remain   invisible under any circumstances.
如果你动了  就当你被杀了
If you move, assume you've been killed.
动了
Moved.
减一分
Minus one point.
减分
Minus.
看看你那把1963年的德拉贡诺夫狙击步枪
Have a look   at your 1963 Dragunov sniper rifle.
用过时的7.62 × 54毫米子弹
With its obsolete   7.62 by 54 mm ammunition,
它的工作距离
it has a working distance
大约600米
of approximately 600 meters.
相比之下
In contrast,
新式8.6×70 拉普·马格南狙击枪
modern 8.6 by 70 Lapua Magnum
或12.7×99 BMG狙击枪
or 12.7 by 99 BMG...
即使在2000米处
rifles hit targets...
也能击中目标
even at 2,000 meters.
你的步枪能射多远
And how far does your rifle shoot?
雷明顿308口径的工作距离为…
Remington 308 caliber   has a working distance of...
大约800米
about 800 meters.
如果敌人的枪法更好呢
And if the enemy has a better shot?
那你就不走运了
Then you are unlucky.
这被称为弹道漏洞
This is called a ballistic vulnerability.
但并不是步枪让狙击手变得危险...
But it's not a rifle   that makes a sniper dangerous...
而是他的智慧和耐力
But his intelligence and endurance.
下一个任务...
The next task...
做好准备
be ready.
狙击手必须始终保持稳定和专注
The sniper must always be stable   and focused.
上膛
Charge!
瞄准
Take aim.
准备好了
Ready.
一  二  三...开火
One, two, three... Fire!
好的
Plus.
准备好了
Ready.
一  二  三...开火
One, two, three... Fire!
好的
Plus.
准备好了
Ready.
一  二  三...开火
One, two, three... Fire!
减分
Minus.
用这样的枪是不可能击中的
It's not possible with such a firearm!
有些人成功了
Some succeeded.
狙击手最重要的技能之一
One of the important skills a sniper
必须具备的是快速心算的能力
has to have is the ability to be able   to calculate quickly in your head.
你的眼睛会被观察事物所占据
Your eyes will be occupied   with observing things.
忘掉计算器吧
Forget about the calculator.
为了确定距离
To determine the distance,
你必须把物体的大小乘以1000
you must multiply   the size of the object by 1000
然后除以视线范围内的点数
and divide by the number   of points in sight.
所以我们要做的是确定到卡玛斯（俄制卡车）的距离
So the task is to determine   the distance to the KAMAZ.
卡玛斯的高度是3.45...
The height of the KAMAZ is 3.45...
刻度尖指向7
and has seven points,
装甲运兵车的高度...
The height   of the armored personnel carrier...
是2.35...
is 2.35...
刻度尖指向2.5
and has 2.5 points.
车厢宽度...
Tank width...
3.46...
请允许我...
Allow me...
有什么不清楚的吗  瑞文
Is something unclear, Raven?
- 我想给出答案   - 说说看
- I want to give the answer.   - Try it.
距离卡玛斯493米
Distance to KAMAZ is 493 meters.
正确
That's right.
940米和804.5米
940 meters and 804 and a half.
装甲运兵车和坦克
To the armored personnel carrier   and to the tank accordingly.
不错  乌鸦
Not bad, Raven.
开枪前  每个人都要大声喊出代码
Before the shot,   everyone should call his code out loud.
“绿色代码”表示我会射击
"Code green" for I can shoot.
“红色代码”表示我不能开枪
"Code red" for I can't shoot.
做好准备
Get ready!
注意
Attention!
Three,
2  1...
two, one...
绿色代码
Code green.
鲍勃  减分
Bob, minus.
巴德  加分
Bad, plus.
雅图  加分
Yartur, plus.
克里姆  加分
Klym, plus.
莫尔  减分
Mor, minus.
杜内  加分
Dunay, plus.
乌鸦  减分...
Raven, minus...
考试结束  所有人放下武器
Exam completed.   Discharge everyone's weapons.
乌鸦  你没听到命令吗
Raven, haven't you heard the command?
考试还没结束
The exam is not over yet.
为什么
Why is that?
我没开枪
I didn't shoot.
你要等到天亮吗
Are you going to wait for dawn?
代码是绿色
The code is green!
喔哦  厉害的爆能枪
Wow, holy Blaster!
加3分  乌鸦
Plus three, Raven.
让您久等了
Thank you for waiting.
克里姆
Klym!
是的  长官
Yes sir!
二等兵
Second-class.
祝贺你
Congratulations.
我为乌克兰人民服务
I serve the Ukrainian people!
杜内
Dunay!
是  长官
Yes sir!
三等兵  祝贺你
Third-class. Congratulations.
我为乌克兰人民服务
I serve the Ukrainian people!
乌鸦
Raven!
是  长官
Yes sir!
一等兵
First-class.
祝贺你
Congratulations.
我为乌克兰人民服务
I serve the Ukrainian people!
- 巴德   - 是  长官
- Bad!   - Yes sir!
二等兵  祝贺你
Second-class. Congratulations...
♪ 告诉我  为什么会这样 ♪
Tell me, why did this happen?
♪ 为什么我的世界  配不上你的世界 ♪
Why is it that my world   Is not enough for your world?
♪ 我俩碰在了一起 ♪
The two of us touched for a moment
♪ 时间在我们身边狡猾地流逝 ♪
And time passes us by craftily
♪ 现在没人知道该去哪里 ♪
Nobody knows where to go now
♪ 没有人在家等着 ♪
Nobody is waiting at home
♪ 投入  爱你的意志 ♪
Dive in, love your will
♪ 但不要在痛苦中迷失方向 ♪
But don't get lost in the pain
♪ 唤醒  唤醒你自己的力量 ♪
And awaken, awaken strength in yourself
♪ 增强自己的力量 ♪
Build strength in yourself
♪ 亲爱的  亲爱的... ♪
My dear, my dear...
♪ 我希望我们有翅膀... ♪
I wish we had wings...
我们需要回到原点
We need to go to the zero line   to our positions.
他们占领了我们在桥上的检查站
Here they captured our checkpoint   on the bridge.
我人手不够...
I don't have enough people...
我们需要在他们加强力量之前清理干净
We need to clean up   before they get strengthened.
他们有什么
What do they have?
没有装甲车  没有重武器  我们会处理
No armor, nothing heavy. We'll handle it.
那些机枪手呢
And the machine gunners?
卡拉什尼科夫轻机枪
Pokemon and RPK.
好吧  带上狙击手和突击队
Okay, take the snipers and assault team.
好的
Plus.
- 大家好   - 我们也祝你好
- Hello, guys.   - We wish you good health!
- 沃伦...   - 是  长官
- Voron...   - Aye, sir.
带上你的装备
Pack up your staff.
是  长官  中校
Yes, sir, Lieutenant Colonel.
第三号就位
Third in position.
第一号就位
First in position.
第二号准备好了
The second is ready.
距离是多少
What is the distance?
400米
400 meters.
两个
Two up.
你的机枪手在左边
Your machine gunner is on the left,
我干掉右边那个
I'm working on the right.
好
Plus.
准备好
Ready.
准备好了
Prepared.
倒计时
Countdown.
收到
Plus.
Two,
1...
one...
- 9点方向车子进入   - 停
- Car on 9!   - Stop!
队长  车上是2个平民
Cap, machine. Two civilians.
从车里出来
Get out of the car!
证件
Documents.
- 把护照给我   - 小心你的手  贱人
- Give me my passport!   - Watch your hands, bitch!
等等
Wait.
好的
Plus.
注意
Attention!
倒计时
Countdown.
3...
Three...
2...
two...
one!
谈谈
Contact.
退回去  贱人
Get back, bitch!
目标是人质背后的一名武装分子
The target   is a militant behind the hostage.
我在人质附近作战
I operate near the hostage.
躺下  笨蛋
Lie down, stupid!
击中  已清除
Hit. Clean!
祝贺您第一次成功完成任务
Congratulations   on your first successful task.
清除
Clean!
过来
Come on.
你们好  伙计们
Hello guys.
- 恭喜你们  孩子们   - 你好
- Congratulations, boys!   - Hello.
- 克里姆和杜内在吗   - 我不清楚
- Are Klym and Dunay here?   - I am not sure.
巴德
Bad!
你好
Hello.
克里姆和杜内在哪里
Where are Klym and Dunay?
在执行任务
On the mission.
杜内...
Dunay...
克里姆在哪里
Where is Klym?
你打听到了什么
What did you find out?
医生说  克里姆体内的子弹像一朵花一样裂开
The medic said that the bullet   in Klym's body opened like a flower,
一些碎片穿过
some fragments passed through,
还有一些卡在了防弹钢板上
and others got stuck in the armor plate.
这家伙根本没机会
The guy had no chance.
能贯穿车辆
The vehicle breaks through,
对于我们肉身还能说些什么...
what can we say about the body...
他们想打击我们的士气
they want to demoralize us.
就是这样
So that's it.
我们要迅速占领在原点处的战壕
We need to quickly occupy   our trench at the zero line,
我们撤离的地方
where ours were evacuated.
沿着这片森林地带绕行  在这里发现了敌人DRG（俄罗斯联邦军事情报人员组成）
Take a detour along this forest strip, the DRG enemy was noticed here.
我给你一个突击小组做掩护
I'll give you an assault group to cover.
当你们占领战壕时
As you occupy the trench,
留意他们的位置  就在附近
keep an eye   on their positions here, nearby.
只是要小心
Just be careful,
那里可能有狙击手
there may be a sniper somewhere.
如果清除干净了
If it's clean,
我会派一个连去那里加强防守
I'll send a company to strengthen it.
接受吧
Follow.
好的
Plus.
哥萨克人  还有五分钟
Cossacks, five minutes left.
报告...
Report...
第一个点很清楚
First clear.
收到
Plus.
距离120
Distance 120.
收到
Plus.
队长  3点方向  我看到一个5人小组
Cap, third post. I see a group of five.
俄罗斯制服  自信地上了绿坡迎接你们了  收到了吗
Russian uniform, confidently going   on the green to meet you, do you roger?
收到
Plus.
倒数25  击杀目标
The goal will be in 25.
20...
Twenty...
15...
Fifteen...
Ten,
9...
nine...
伊凡
Ivan?
Six,
five,
four,
three,
two,
one.
开火
Fire!
干得好
Good job.
- 我们结束了  完成任务   - 很好
- We're done, finish it.   - Plus-plus.
伊凡是谁
Who is Ivan?
我以前在奥尔洛夫卡的学生
My former student from Horlivka.
他做出了自己的选择
He made his choice.
我也一样...
As did I...
嗯  是啊  糟糕透顶
Huh, yeah. Piece of shit.
有什么事吗
So what's up?
延伸检查
Stretches checked.
悄悄地爬过去是不可能的
It will not be possible   to climb through quietly.
照片里是谁
Who is in the photo?
家人
Family.
我能看看吗
Can I have a look?
我妻子斯维特拉娜
My wife Svitlana
还有女儿们  维卡和密罗斯瓦
and daughters, Vika and Myroslava.
孩子们现在知道你在哪吗
Do the kids know where you are now?
不知道
No.
他们以为我在出差
They think that I'm on a business trip.
我和我妻子一致认为  如果他们知道的少一些  他们就会睡得更好
My wife and I agreed that   if they know less, they will sleep better.
这就是为什么她担心那里的每个人
That's why she's worried   about everyone there.
明白了
Got it.
这是你的护身符吗
Is this your amulet?
这是我的...
This is my...
家人
family.
他们的位置在这里
Their positions are here.
留意他们
Keep an eye on them.
是的  我明白  克里斯特尔
Yes, I understand. Crystal.
是的  当然  尼古拉·伊万尼奇
Yes, of course, Nikolai Ivanych,
我们会尽力的  别担心
we will do everything, don't worry.
另一边  我们需要更多
On the other side, we need more.
五分钟  快点  快点
Five minutes. Come on, come on.
明白  我正在努力
Understood, I'm working.
武器检查了吗
Are the weapons checked?
电池  对讲机
Batteries, walkie-talkies,
- 急救包   - 我们都有
- first aid kits.   - We have it!
一切都有
Everything is there!
把旗拿下来  妈的...
Take off the flag, fuck...
- 没错  该死  兄弟   - 快点
- Exactly! Shoot, bro!   - Come on.
剪掉正常的树枝就行了  你为什么拖着这玩意
Just cut the normal branches,   why are you dragging this shit.
这里有两个
Here they have two.
这里是一挺机枪和一对狙击手
Here is a machine gun and a sniper pair.
- 你能藏好吗   - 是啊
- Will you cover-up?   - Yeah.
你需要助手吗
Do you need an assistant?
我会搞定
I'll handle it.
- 都准备好了   - 让大家都进去
- Everything is ready.   - Let's get everyone inside.
- 进去   - 启动引擎
- Get inside!   - Start engine!
- 启动引擎   - 出发
- Start engine!   - Let's go!
11点方向有辆车
At 11 o'clock there is a car.
我看到了
I see.
汽车附近有2名武装分子
Two militants near the car.
继续观察
Continue observation.
一个手持机枪的战士
A fighter with a machine gun.
代码是绿色  我可以击杀
The code is green. I can work!
我不允许你这么做
I do not allow you to.
保持观察
Keep observing.
一个手持机枪的战士
A fighter with a machine gun.
代码是绿色  我可以击杀
The code is green. I can work!
关上保险
Put on the fuse!
一个手持机枪的战士  代码是绿色  我射杀了
A fighter with a machine gun!   The code is green! I'm shooting!
关上保险  这是命令
Put on the safety. That is an order!
混蛋
Motherfucker!
离我有200米
I have 200!
狙击手在10点方向
Sniper at 10 o'clock!
狙击手  在十点方向  距离200米
Sniper! On the tenth! Distance 200.
干掉第一个
The first minus.
第二个在K4区
Second in the sector K4.
收到  我们正在行动
Yes. We are working.
我问了上面...
I asked at the top...
特勤局会去找杀死队长的凶手
Secret services will look   for the killer of the Cap.
当有消息时
When there is information,
我会打电话给你
I'll call you
而且你会处理好的
and you will deal with it.
你明白了吗
Do you understand?
解散
Dismissed.
队长...
Captain...
我们该走了
It's time for us.
雅库特
Yakut.
你有发现什么
What do you have?
我要在这里趴多久
How long will I be lying here?
我一周都洗不掉这屎味了
I won't be able   to wash off this shit for a week.
耐心点  马卡尔  你会在我的屎里躺一辈子
Be patient, Makar.   You will lie in my shit all my life.
滚蛋
Fuck off.
我不管了
I waved everything.
我要爬到你那边
I will crawl to you.
马卡尔  回答
Makar, respond.
操  你在哪里  你被干掉了吗
Fuck. Where are you, have you fallen?
你  贱人
You, bitch.
世界上第三大
The third-largest nuclear arsenal
核武库
in the world.
并且在1994年
And in 1994 a memorandum was signed
乌克兰、俄罗斯、英国和美国签署了一份备忘录...
between Ukraine, Russia,   Great Britain, and the USA...
这是正确的
That's right.
核不扩散备忘录保证了乌克兰的独立
The memorandum on non-proliferation   guaranteed Ukraine's independence,
主权和边界
sovereignty, and borders.
我们都知道俄罗斯是如何尊重其他国家的边界的...
We all know how Russia respects   the borders of other states...
所以这个问题的解决方案...
So the solution to this problem...
旅长
BRIGADE COMMANDER
请说
Speaking.
他在霍尔洛夫卡附近有点活跃
It lit up near Horlivka.
他干掉了我们两名侦察兵
He fired two of our scouts.
范围大吗
Was it in a wide range?
是的
Yes.
第一次是两天前  第二次  是今天
The first, two days ago.   The second, today.
来自同一个位置吗
From one position?
不在电话上说  会议上说  做好准备
Not by the phone.   At the meeting. Get ready.
身份证
ID?
开走
Drive.
打开
Open it.
代号埃尔布鲁斯  二等兵
Code name Elbrus, second-class.
祝贺你
Congratulations.
- 贝斯特  三等兵  恭喜你   - 是
- Beast, third-class, congratulations.   - Yeah.
- 雷  三等兵...   - 是
- Ray, third-class...   - Yes.
祝贺你
Congratulations.
- 祝贺你   - 我为乌克兰人民服务
- Congratulations.   - I serve the Ukrainian people!
- 你还好吧   - 活着
- How are you?   - Alive.
给你这个
Got you this.
谢谢
Thank you.
- 你好   - 你好
- Hello!   - Hi!
学员们  放松点  拿上你们的东西  上车
Cadets, at ease.   Grab your stuff and get in the car.
乌鸦...
Raven...
是的
Aye.
- 准备好了吗   - 是的  长官
- Ready?   - Yes sir.
跟我来
Follow me.
请大家注意
Attention to all.
最近  情报部门向我们提供了...
Recently, intelligence provided us   with information...
放幻灯片
Show the slide.
俄罗斯狙击手  代号“塞里”
Russian sniper. Call sign "Sery".
在长距离  大多是1.5公里的情况下  使用12.7
Works with 12.7 over long distances,   mostly 1.5 km.
子弹的范围很广
The bullets are wide-ranging.
他已经杀死了我们5名狙击手和3名机枪手
He has already killed five of our snipers   and three machine gunners.
网站显示
Show the site.
他发布他的视频来打击我们的士气
He publishes his videos to demoralize us.
在其中一个视频里  是我们的队长
In one of these videos, is our Cap.
妈的
Shit!
昨天我们的狙击手
Yesterday our sniper
在河边一家化工厂  被同一颗子弹
was killed by the same bullet   between armor plates
穿过防弹钢板击中身亡
near a chemical plant next to the river.
今天也是一样  他们在同一个区域袭击
Today was the same,   they hit in the same sector.
他们没有改变位置吗
They didn't change position?
在那个区域布雷
Cover it with mines.
这行不通
It won't work.
乌鸦  你是本地人  跟他们解释一下
Raven, you are a local,   explain to the guys.
化工厂里有个高压氯气储存库
There is a chlorine storage under pressure   in the chemical plant.
好吧  去他妈的  让他们下地狱吧
Well, fuck them.   PTUR him to the damn mother.
- 保证钢瓶爆炸   - 那又怎样
- Explosion of cylinders is guaranteed.   - So what?
环境灾难
Environmental disaster.
操
Fuck.
大家都明白了吗
Is that clear to everyone?
计划如下  地图
The plan is as follows. Map.
该区域共有8名武装分子
There are a total of eight militants   on the territory.
狙击手可能就在一栋大楼里
The sniper himself is probably   in a building
那里有氯气仓库
where there are warehouses with chlorine.
而且他的2名观察员可能在这层楼里
Plus two of his observers   are probably on the floors.
所以
So,
第一对狙击手干掉1号
the first pair of snipers   takes the first fighter.
第二和第三是这些目标
The second and third are these targets.
第四个和第五是这两个
The fourth and fifth are these two.
最后的目标
And the final targets,
2名观察员...
two observers...
和塞里
and Sery.
有什么意义  无论如何  我们又不能打爆那氯气罐
What's the point? Anyway, we cannot   shoot this chlorine under pressure.
我们的任务只是清除通道
Our task is to clear the access only.
然后呢
And then what?
然后乌鸦爬着靠近他
Then Raven climbs up to him.
有问题吗
Questions?
做好准备
Get ready.
乌鸦  通报情况
Raven, status.
三个小时了
Three hours.
收到
Plus.
1号
First.
在预定位子
In position.
2号
Second.
在预定位子
In position.
乌鸦  通报情况...
Raven, status...
进入预定位子
In position...
啊  和平主义者...
Ah, pacifist...
我当时就应该杀了你...
I should have shot you then...
- 清除   - 收到
- Clear.   - Plus.
注意  准备就绪  报告...
Attention, readiness. Report...
一组准备就绪
First ready.
二组准备就绪
Second ready.
三组准备就绪
Third ready.
五组就绪...
Fifth ready...
我看到目标  代码是绿色
I see the target, the code is green.
倒计时...
Countdown...
Five,
four,
three,
two,
one.
谁在开火
Whose fire?
他妈的我不知道  那个白痴在某个地方流泪
Fuck if I know.   The moron is watering somewhere.
报告
Report!
清除
Clear.
- 乌鸦  行动   - 收到
- Raven, work.   - Plus.
1号
First.
2号
Second.
在位
In place.
报告
Report.
小组  报告...
Group, report...
小组  报告
Group, report.
- 1号与小组联系不上   - 2号  向我报告
- There is no connection with the group.   - Second, report to me.
塞里
Sery!
- 坚守阵地   - 是
- Hold your position!   - Yes.
操
Fuck.
- 2号...   - 在位
- Second...   - In place.
- 布朗   - 是的
- Brown.   - Affirmative.
- 我需要200人支援   - 怎么了?
- I have one 200.    - What happened?
狙击手
Sniper.
明白  那些安全小组呢
Clear. What about the security group?
联系不上
No connection.
明白了  十分钟  坚守阵地
Got it. Ten minutes. Hold your position.
是
Yes.
2号
Second.
在位
In place.
回到你的位置  守住入口
Return to your position   and guard the entrance.
是
Yes.
操...
Fuck...
塞里  收到了吗
Sery. Do you copy?
塞里  支援部队来了  收到了吗
Sery, arrived with a group. Do you copy?
你们这些混蛋要为克里米亚事件负责
You shitbags will answer us for Crimea.
- 清除   - 清除
- Clean.   - Clean.
乌鸦  周边安全
Raven, the perimeter is clean.
收到
Plus.
让他和我在一起吧...
Let him stay with me...
主啊  用你的手指引
Guide your hand, Lord,
去消灭在这片土地上...
to destroy all enemies...
的敌人
on this land.
字幕翻译 - 静默的风
如转载使用  请保留译者信息
翻译字幕纯属学习交流
不作商业用途